This script was designed to clean physiological data for later analysis and was written in BIOPAC Basic. If you are not familiar with this coding language, it is important to have a little background to understand the structure of the script.

BIOPAC Basic is a proprietary offshoot of Visual Basic and is used to automate the AcqKnowledge physio data processing app. If you are not familiar with this language, it only has a set number of variables with pre-defined scopes and lacks certain standard features, such as for loops and user-defined functions. Instead, it favours various forms of "Goto" commands and labels. For loops are emulated by sandwiching the looped code between a label and a Goto command and using if statements to skip the Goto command once a condition is met. User functions are replaced with "Macros," which are essentially separate scripts that are run when called upon using "Call." You can not pass any values to a macro; instead a subset of variables are set to be shared by all macro functions and thus, any data that needs to be passed to the macro must be saved to those variables.